<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Robots Have Feelings</title>
    <link>https://erickrdiaz.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Robots Have Feelings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 18:25:58 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://erickrdiaz.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What I Like About Node</title>
      <link>https://erickrdiaz.com/posts/what-i-like-about-node/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 18:25:58 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erickrdiaz.com/posts/what-i-like-about-node/</guid>
      <description>I Dig Node I remember when I was a fledgling programmer and Node was something I had just learned about; I remember thinking &amp;ldquo;Server-side Javascript? That sounds like the worst thing ever&amp;rdquo;. After tinkering with it and working with it professionally for about a year, I had a change of heart. Node fulfills a specific niche on the web, and it does the job well. Critics will often point to Node&amp;rsquo;s error-handling capabilites, single-threadedness, type-safety (and other JS specific issues) as deal-breakers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firebase Push Notifications</title>
      <link>https://erickrdiaz.com/posts/firebase-push-notifications/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2017 12:35:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erickrdiaz.com/posts/firebase-push-notifications/</guid>
      <description>Principles and Patterns (I wax lyrically a bit about software design; if you just want the code click here)
My Principles and Patterns of Software Design class (what a mouthful) was one of the most important classes I took during my time at UVU. Most of the subject matter was based off of a modified set of GoF patterns. Whether you love or hate the patterns, you have to admit that they were and continue to be an influencing force in the software development world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dabbling in C&#43;&#43; Again</title>
      <link>https://erickrdiaz.com/posts/dabbling-in-c&#43;&#43;-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 09:38:46 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erickrdiaz.com/posts/dabbling-in-c&#43;&#43;-again/</guid>
      <description>C++ is weird Some people love it and others would rather remove their fingernails with pliers than program in it. I find myself falling in both camps; sometimes at the same time. I have an inkling that my software engineering journey has a lot to do with my feelings towards it. C++ is my&amp;hellip; educational progenitor language maybe? Essentially I was forced to use it all throughout my university experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacktoberfest Part 1</title>
      <link>https://erickrdiaz.com/posts/hacktoberfest-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 09:01:14 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erickrdiaz.com/posts/hacktoberfest-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Fall is here The weather is getting cooler; leaves are changing color, the wind is picking up, and people are cracking jokes about pumpkin spice lattes left and right. October is here, and with it,
Hacktoberfest If you don&amp;rsquo;t know what that is, here is a short snippet from the official Hacktoberfest website
 Hacktoberfest is a month-long celebration of open source software
 Simple enough explanation. I decided to participate for a couple of reasons:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://erickrdiaz.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erickrdiaz.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello! Hey folks. I&amp;rsquo;m Erick Diaz. I&amp;rsquo;m a software engineer at Yours and can be found most places online under the handle Bearlock. I&amp;rsquo;m a Utah native that digs exploring all it has to offer with my wife and four dogs. I&amp;rsquo;m interested in all sorts of technologies, philosophies, and bits of useless trivia.
Games I&amp;rsquo;m playin&amp;rsquo;:  Hitman series Overwatch Super Mario 64 (120 stars baby!)  Books I&amp;rsquo;m readin&amp;rsquo;:  In the Realm of Hungry Ghosts It Devours!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing Cloud Functions</title>
      <link>https://erickrdiaz.com/posts/testing-cloud-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 14:15:54 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erickrdiaz.com/posts/testing-cloud-functions/</guid>
      <description>Click me if you wanna get right to testing It is now 2017 Happy belated new year.
Its been about nine months now. Change is constant and inevitable. In this year alone I have:
 Gotten a new and exciting job, Bought a beautiful dream-home, and Began wrapping up my last year of college  Several big and life-altering changes. Its sad to say, but writing here took a backseat to the other priorities in my life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>End of Year Retrospective</title>
      <link>https://erickrdiaz.com/posts/end-of-year-retrospective/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erickrdiaz.com/posts/end-of-year-retrospective/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been quite a year Turns out when school is in session, I&amp;rsquo;m not the best at keeping this thing updated; my apologies. I feel like that&amp;rsquo;s okay though. I may not be great at keeping on top of this, but I still have a vested interest in maintaining this blog &amp;ndash; at least, when I have some free time (whoo winter break!). As usual, and according to the dictates of the universe, I&amp;rsquo;m busy with school, work, side-projects, friends, video-games; the list goes on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Status Update</title>
      <link>https://erickrdiaz.com/posts/a-status-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erickrdiaz.com/posts/a-status-update/</guid>
      <description>Whoa, hey It&amp;rsquo;s been a while right? I barely recognize you (or myself). It&amp;rsquo;s been about four months now with nary an update or peep out of me. Not really good attendance. To be honest, I feel a bit guilty. Not too guilty mind you &amp;ndash; just a bit. Life has been more unexpected than I expected. Things came up, things happened, balls were dropped, mistakes were made, assignments were overdue, vacations were had, companies closed, and opportunites arose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Messing with Lakka and a Chromebox</title>
      <link>https://erickrdiaz.com/posts/messing-with-lakka-and-chromebox/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erickrdiaz.com/posts/messing-with-lakka-and-chromebox/</guid>
      <description>What to do One of the biggest issues I face when I get a new project-computer or toy is the dilemma of picking what to do with it. The computer itself is a blank slate; truly a paragon of hope, and possibility. It gets to the point where I get overwhelmed with all the choices I have. There are quite literally hundreds of projects that I drown in the fractals of choice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Open Source</title>
      <link>https://erickrdiaz.com/posts/importance-of-open-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erickrdiaz.com/posts/importance-of-open-source/</guid>
      <description>Free and Open Source Software Open source software is quickly becoming a necessary staple and cornerstone to software development itself and the advancement thereof. A recent(ish) study conducted by Black Duck Software (OSS logistics and legal problem solver) and North Bridge (venture capitalists that grow businesses) displayed just how important open source projects are becoming - at least in the corporate and business sphere. The aforementioned survey showed some pretty interesting results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Practical Python Projects: A Case Study</title>
      <link>https://erickrdiaz.com/posts/practical-python-projects-a-case-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erickrdiaz.com/posts/practical-python-projects-a-case-study/</guid>
      <description>Python&amp;rsquo;s Such a Pretty Language Revisiting old Python code is always such a treat. Its easy to see what was going on and what the code is actually doing. It is so simple to trace and read, rarely do I ever ask myself &amp;gt;What idiot wrote this?
Only to later find out through a commit or comment that I was in fact the idiot burgeoning genius that wrote it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring Semester Reflections and Impressions</title>
      <link>https://erickrdiaz.com/posts/spring-semester-reflections-and-impressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erickrdiaz.com/posts/spring-semester-reflections-and-impressions/</guid>
      <description>Reflections on the past few weeks For the past few weeks I have been immersing myself deeply in the essential core of my 5 classes and studying diligently day and night.
Was that convincing enough? I hope so. Its what I keep telling myself that I&amp;rsquo;m doing.
In reality I&amp;rsquo;ve been panicking, mentally sprinting to keep up, and trying to juggle work, school, and home life (buh-bye social life and hobbies!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Year, New Resolutions</title>
      <link>https://erickrdiaz.com/posts/new-year-new-resolutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erickrdiaz.com/posts/new-year-new-resolutions/</guid>
      <description>And so, with barely a chance to anticipate and prepare for it, the new year is upon us. Entering a new year has always been a reflective process for me; Usually I&amp;rsquo;m filled with equal parts determination and excitement punctuated with a hint of personal, not self-loathing, maybe self-disappointment is a better word. The new year comes and I typically find myself looking at my year in review. Like most, my subconscious takes mental inventory of all the good, bad, and strange that may have happened throughout the year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Games and Firsts: A Case Study</title>
      <link>https://erickrdiaz.com/posts/on-games-and-firsts-a-case-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erickrdiaz.com/posts/on-games-and-firsts-a-case-study/</guid>
      <description>First posts deserve a look at my first projects, at least, that&amp;rsquo;s the line of thinking and reasoning that has been bouncing around my head for a bit. I shall declare this my First Case Study. The first class that had me cobble together an interactive, non-console, and non-trivial project was my web programming class. The class reinforced some concepts I already &amp;ldquo;knew&amp;rdquo; (basic HTML and DOM manipulation) and introduced me to stuff that was kinda magical (HTTP GET and POST requests, server vs client side storage, cookies, etc).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Actually doing it</title>
      <link>https://erickrdiaz.com/posts/actually-doing-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erickrdiaz.com/posts/actually-doing-it/</guid>
      <description>Hey! The name&amp;rsquo;s Erick. This is my initial foray into using Pelican as a way to manage a &amp;lsquo;blog&amp;rsquo;. I&amp;rsquo;ve always intended to start one up but never quite committed. I&amp;rsquo;ve built my own pseudo-blog in Django, I&amp;rsquo;ve dabbled with Ghost, and I have extensive experience using Wordpress to build sites for others; Django was great, but it was a bit heavy for what I was intending on doing. It seems like a great way to build an application (with a blog maybe tacked on).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>